A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Project and Event Photographs, Accession 2018:033 FA1441
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Project and Event Photographs, Accession 2018:033
1960-2002
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1441
1.7 Cubic Feet 4 boxes (2 legal document containers and 2 letter document containers)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas. During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2018 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accession 2018:033.
Arrangement
Arranged as received from the Ford Foundation.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains prints, slides, and negatives from Ford Foundation program events and projects, including the Operation Life Community Development's grand opening, artwork from Black and Hispanic art museums, the Program Associates Farewell Reception, and visits to the Philippines.
Philippines; Art museums -- United States; Arts and culture; Photographs
- Operation Life Community Development Corporation's Grand Opening, 1988 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Grant No.: 08400723
- Operation Life Medical Center and Business Office Building's Grand Opening, 1982 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Support for Black and Hispanic Art Museums - The Ohio Historical Society, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Grant No.: 09351000
- Support for Black and Hispanic Art Museums - Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Grant No.: 09101052
- Support for Black and Hispanic Art Museums - Morgan State University, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Grant No.: 09101054
- Support for Black and Hispanic Art Museums - Fisk University, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Grant No.: 09101048
- Support for Black and Hispanic Art Museums - The Mexican Museum, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Grant No.: 08900644
- Support for Black and Hispanic Art Museums - Commonwealth Corporation, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Grant No.: 09400902
- Support for Black and Hispanic Art Museums - Institute of Puerto Rican Culture, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Grant No.: 09101051
- Support for Black and Hispanic Art Museums - Educational Testing and Assessment, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Grant No.: 09290006
- Support for Black and Hispanic Art Museums - North Carolina Central University, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Grant No.: 09101059; Also includes box records related to Ford Archive/photocopy logs
- Program Associates Farewell Reception - Prints, 2002 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Program Associates Farewell Reception - Prints (Duplicates), 2002 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Program Associates Farewell Reception - Negatives, 2002 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Media, Arts, and Culture Group Pictures, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Photographs - Former President of the Philippines Corazon C. Aquino, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Photographs - Philippines I, 1960-2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Photographs - Philippines II (3 folders), 1960-2000 (Box 3, Folder 18-20)
- Photographs - Philippines III (4 folders), 1960-2000 (Box 3, Folder 21, Box 4, Folder 22-24)
  Event at Makati Shangri-La
- Photographs - Philippines IV, 1960-2000 (Box 4, Folder 25)